A Guide to the Ford Foundation records, Office of the Secretary, General Office Files FA693
Rockefeller Archive Center
Ford Foundation records, Office of the Secretary, General Office Files
1954-1998
Rockefeller Archive Center
Ford Foundation
FA693
2.4 Cubic Feet
Separated Materials
Appendix A: Reports – Unpublished reports written by Ford Foundation staff and consultants were removed from their original folders, scanned and transferred to the Archives' collection of staff and consultant reports. See Appendix A for a list of these reports and their specific assigned number. The reports are listed in alphabetical order by author. The assigned number may be used to access reports in the online catalog.
Conditions Governing Access note
Material is open for scholarly research, with prior archival review.
Material more than ten years old is open for scholarly research.
Select individual files are restricted, as noted. Permission to access these files must be obtained from the Ford Foundation before scholarly access is permitted.
Immediate Source of Acquisition note
Ford Foundation archive was deposited at RAC in 2011. Ford Foundation records, correspondence, reports, program files and officers papers were transferred to, and accessioned by, RAC beginning in 2011. Accessions continue as necessary.
Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements note
Materials requiring specialized equipment for access (film, audio, video, slides) may be restricted from scholarly research dependent on availability of the applicable equipment. Brittle or damaged items, or materials otherwise in need of preservation care, may be restricted from scholarly research at the discretion of the RAC Head of Archival Services/RAC Head of Reference.
Ford Foundation
- Subject Files, 1954-1998; I
  - Appropriations Procedure and Ford Foundation Budget, 1970-1991 (Box 1)
  - Basic Data on the Ford Foundation incl. History of the Ford Foundation Reports, Drafts, Historical Financial Report from 1954, 1954-1995 (Box 1)
  - Bequests and Gifts -- General, 1968-1993 (Box 1)
  - Congressional Letters -- How to Handle Congressional Letters Initiated by Office of Reports (Box 1)
  - Congressional Letters and Distribution of Ford Foundation Printed Materials, 1982-1995 (Box 1)
  - Dissolution of Ford Foundation Assets, 1974-1984 (Box 1)
  - Ford Estates -- Henry and Edsel -- Mills Committee Hearings Re: Henry and Edsel Bequest to Tax Exempt Foundation, 1969-1978 (Box 1)
  - Ford Foundation and Washington -- Incl. Correspondence with Government Officials, Grants Re: Government Activities and Initiatives, etc., 1970-1985 (Box 1)
  - Government Officials -- Correspondence Re: Ford Foundation Grants, Compensation Regulations for Government Officials, etc., 1980-1992 (Box 1)
  - Government Officials -- Richard Foote Case Re: Compensation for Government Officials, 1976 (Box 1)
    Conditions Governing Access
    Restricted from scholarly access.
  - Indemnification -- Directors and Officers, 1976-1988 (Box 2)
  - Indemnification -- Directors and Officers, 1984-1998 (Box 2)
  - Office of the Secretary General Correspondence -- Incl. Papers, Drafts Re: Functions and Services of OS and General Counsel, 1954-1989 (Box 2)
  - Pensions -- Report Re: Inequality in Pension Benefits for Men and Women, Apr 1977 (Box 2)
  - Real Estate Subsidiaries, 1976-1982 (Box 2)
  - Restructuring Office of the Secretary, Grants Processing, and Individual Grants, 1994 (Box 2)
  - Size of the Ford Foundation -- Correspondence, Reports Re: Pros and Cons of Large Foundations; incl. Summary of Reece Committee Investigation of Tax Exempt Foundations, 1954-1975 (Box 2)
  - Travel Policies, 1964-1990 (Box 2)
- Appendix A: Reports, 1983
  - The Office of the Secretary and General Counsel -- Functions and Services, Mar 30, 1983 (Report #019910)